Bui Tien Dung

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam • +(86) 329816610 • buitiendung199@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/bui-tien-dung-99it

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with almost 3 years experience in Software Development. I have a strong background in Agile/Scrum methodologies and strong knowledge of Front-end development, especially ReactJS and NextJS. I am good at logical thinking, mindset, adaptability and passion to learn new things.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Money C****, Technological Asia

May 2022 - Present

Frontend Developer

This application is a cutting-edge website. It helps users the way to invest, helps the bank to introduce and sell insurance services, funds, stocks. This application has a payment feature by third party wallet. Besides, it helps users estimate and simulate their assets in the future. This application has a CMS service for client edit content on the application. From the success of this application, my company built two other applications based on this one. This project is quite big with 20 members. It has many phases to develop new large features. Moreover, each month, it has the growth to add smaller features, handle request changes for clients.

Stacks FE: NextJS, ReactJS, redux-toolkit, server-side-rendering, client-side-rendering, NextAuth, SCSS module, Typescript, react-chartjs-2, craco, react-router, responsive, Ant Design and many packages of ReactJS ecosystem.

Responsibilities:

- Participate in building new large features.
- Ensuring responsiveness for all devices (PC, tablet, iOS, Android), UI/UX must be correct with design from JP and strict principles.
- Ensuring code must be clean, high performance and refactor code to improve SEO for application.
- Collaborate with developers from JP, review their code before merge.
- I will handle tasks with complicated logic and critical effects like updating flow cart, payment, updating Node version, NextAuth version and other packages.
- Enhance performance for the application on mobile and desktop.
- Management source code for the growth each month, prepare Pull Request to UAT and deployment on production.
- Take the main responsibility for the growth each month, share tasks for other members and support them to complete tasks before the deadline.

Websites of Finatext, Technological Asia

Oct 2021 – Apr 2022

Frontend Developer

Websites of Finatext have information about the Finatext group.

Stacks FE: NuxtJS, VueJS, jQuery, SCSS

Responsibilities:

- Support maintain UI/UX on all websites of Finatext group.
- Integration html, css and js from third party into NuxtJS.

Trading Forex, Technological Asia

May 2021 – May 2022

Frontend Developer

Trading Forex is an application for user experience with trading forex like Exness. Users can sell and buy currency pairs, profit or loss is dependent on the increase or decrease of currency pair exchange rate. This application uses micro frontend, realtime.

Stacks FE: Micro Frontend, ReactJS, styled-components, socket, webpack, Typescript, redux saga, echart-for-react, adobe analytics.

Responsibilities:

- Add new features, enhance old features for applications.
- Ensuring responsive, friendly user-interface and smooth user-experience on mobile devices (iOS, Android).
- Refactor code and improve performance for application.

EDUCATION

VNUHCM - University of Science, Ho Chi Minh

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

Minh 2017 - 2022

SKILLS

Computer Science:

- Good logical thinking, mindset, clean code and optimization.
- Have knowledge about OOP, Functional Programming.

Technical Skills:

- Languages and Scripting: Javascript/Typescript (proficient), SQL/NoSQL (have knowledge)
- Front-end: ReactJS, NextJS, CSS/SCSS, HTML, Responsive (proficient), State Management (redux toolkit), Tailwind Css (intermediate), NextAuth, react-chartjs-2, react-query, Jest, VueJS, NuxtJS (have knowledge).
- **Backend:** NodeJS, ExpressJS (have knowledge)
- Others: Git.

Non-Technical Skills:

- Good teamworks.
- Fast adaptability.

Business Domain: Bank, Finance, Forex.

Methodologies: Agile/Scrum